KAIYUAN TAN

BIOGRAPHY

I am currently a **Ph.D. student** at the Department of Computer Science, **Vanderbilt University**. My research goal is to build a safe and robust cyber-physical system. My recent work focuses on optimization-based adversarial attacks and learning-enabled control and planning.

Research Interests: Physics-informed Machine Learning, Adversarial Attack, Optimization

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Jan 2024 - Current

Vanderbilt University, TN, USA Advisor: Dr. Thomas Beckers

Research Focus: "Physics-informed Machine Learning"

M.S. in Electrical Engineering

Aug 2021 - May 2023

Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA

Advisor: Dr. Yiannis Kantaros

Thesis: "Targeted Adversarial Attack Generation and Detection"

B.Eng. in Information Engineering

Aug 2017 - May 2021

Sun Yat-Sen University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China

Advisor: Dr. Lei Sun

Thesis: "Estimation of mixed noise parameters depending on hyperspectral images signals"

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Associate Student (Robotics & Learning-Enabled Control)

Aug 2023 - Current

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN, USA

Advisor: Dr. Thomas Beckers

Research Associate Intern (Robotics & Cyber-Physical System Security)

May 2023 - July 2023

Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA

Advisor: Dr. Ning Zhang

Research Associate Student (Adversarial Attack & Learning-Enabled Control)

June 2022 - May 2023

Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA

Advisor: Dr. Yiannis Kantaros

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] **K. Tan**, P. Li, and T. Beckers, "Physics-Constrained Learning of PDE Systems with Uncertainty Quantified Port-Hamiltonian Models." 6th Annual Learning for Dynamics & Control Conference at Oxford (L4DC), 2024.
- [2] **K. Tan**, J. Wang, and Y. Kantaros, "Targeted Adversarial Attacks against Neural Network Trajectory Predictors." 5th Annual Learning for Dynamics & Control Conference at UPenn (**L4DC**), 2023.
- [3] K. Tan, Z. Wang, Z. Liu, and L. Sun, "Research on Full-Space Spectrum-Sharing Strategy for Massive MIMO Cognitive Radio Systems" The 2021 IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics and Computer Engineering (ICCECE), (pp. 639-644). IEEE.

PRE-PRINTS

- [1] J. Wang, Jiaming Tong, **K. Tan**, and Y. Kantaros, "Large Language Model Based Robot Planning with Safety-Guaranteed Temporal Logic Task Specification."
- [2] J. Wang, **K. Tan**, Z. Sun, and Y. Kantaros, "Mission-driven Exploration for Accelerated Deep Reinforcement Learning with Temporal Logic Task Specifications."

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages Python, Matlab, C/C++ **Deep Learning Frameworks** Pytorch

AWARDS

S Award, US Mathematical Contest in Modeling, 2018-2019.